Guide to the Leonid Hurwicz papers, 1911-2008 and undated RL.00599
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research and Writings Series, 1911-2006 and undated, bulk 1945-2006, 142 boxes
  - Other Research and Writings Subseries, 1911-2004 and undated, bulk 1945-2004, 91 boxes
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 170)
      - Monopolistic competition, draft, 1971 (Box 170)
      - Collaboration with Arrow, 1959-1960, 2 folders (Box 170)
      - Hurwicz, On informational requirements for non-wasteful resource allocation systems, draft, 1976 (Box 170)
      - Collaboration with Koopmans, 1950, 1963, 2 folders (Box 170)
      - Collaboration with Radner and Reiter, 1975 (Box 170)
      - Collaboration with Maskin/Postlewaite, Feasible implementation of social choice correspondences by Nash equilibria, draft, 1980 (Box 170)
      - Hurwicz - Decentralization and Resource allocation, 1986 (photocopy) (Box 170)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 171)
      - Collaboration with T.W. Anderson on Statistical disturbances, 1946 (Box 171)
      - Walker, Mark (Box 171)
      - Solow, R., The Economics of Resources, Ely Lecture (Box 171)
      - Oxford, collaboration with Reiter, research and notes, 1990s, 4 folders (Box 171)
      - Scientific American correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 171)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 172)
      - Collaboration with Reiter, Transversals, 1992-1995 (Box 172)
      - Nash Equilibrium (Box 172)
      - Incentive compatibility (Box 172)
      - Reverse engineering, 1993 (Box 172)
    - Correspondence, drafts, notes and printed material (Box 173)
      - Institutional design (Box 173)
      - Mathematical Intelligencer, 1978 (Box 173)
      - Student PhD dissertations (multiple folders) (Box 173)
      - Hurwicz, Specification bias (Box 173)
      - Hurwicz, "Boundedness of Yf" (Box 173)
      - Articles, papers by others (Vind, Grossman, Gorman, Wallace, and others) (Box 173)
    - Drafts, notes, and printed material (Box 174)
      - Collaboration with Reiter and Saari, early notes? (Box 174)
      - With Reiter/Saari, On constucting mechanism with message spaces of minimal dimension for smooth performance functions, draft, 1980 (Box 174)
      - Hurwicz, Early research notes, undated (Box 174)
      - Hurwicz, proof of Lemma B notes, 1986 (Box 174)
      - Collaboration with Kannai, On the demand function generated by a smooth and concavifiable preference ordering (Box 174)
    - Notes, transparencies and printed material (Box 175)
      - Thomson, Kohn triangle, annotated, 1999 (Box 175)
      - Details on Reinhard and Ryder, notes, 2005 (Box 175)
      - Reiter (Box 175)
      - Bergstrom and Cornes, 1981-1983, 3 folders (Box 175)
      - Milgrom, North and Weingast (Box 175)
      - Transparencies (Box 175)
      - Papers by others (multiple folders) (Box 175)
    - Drafts, notes, and printed material (Box 176)
      - Hurwicz, Cores, optima, and almost competitive prices in discrete spaces, 1994 (Box 176)
      - Decision and organization, chapter 14 of Informationally decentralized systems (Box 176)
      - Hurwicz, folder of earliest papers: Systems with non-additive disturbances; Variable parameters in stochastic processes; Least squares bias in time series; and On the theory of investment (1945) (Box 176)
      - Collaboration with Maskin and Postlewaite, feasible Nash implementation (Box 176)
      - Ruttan (Box 176)
      - Mechanism design and institutions, multiple folders with notes and drafts (Box 176)
      - Modeling Institutional Change, Warsaw paper, 1997? (Box 176)
    - Conferences, drafts, notes, transparencies and printed material (Box 177)
      - Modeling Institutional Change, abstract, paper and transparencies, for Warsaw conference, 1997, 2 folders (Box 177)
      - On the existence of incentive-compatible allocation systems, Berlin paper, 1973, draft (Box 177)
      - unspecified (Box 177)
      - Nahorski (Box 177)
      - Warziwoda (Box 177)
      - Contemporary Economic Issues, Chapter 4, 1998 (Box 177)
      - Research proposal, 1989 (Box 177)
      - Hurwicz, early papers: Optimality properties...decentralized economic system, n.d.; Programming in general spaces, 1954 (Box 177)
      - Revisiting externalities, 1998-1999, 2 folders (Box 177)
    - Drafts, notes, transparencies and printed material (Box 178)
      - Collaboration with Richter on Lagrange Multipliers, annotated draft, 2002 (Box 178)
      - Decentralization and mechanisms, multiple drafts and notes, Ithaca, 1991 (Box 178)
      - Katzner on institutions, annotated by Hurwicz, 1989 (Box 178)
      - Hurwicz, Profiles as canonical strategy domains for Nash implementability, drafts, 1982 (Box 178)
      - Hurwicz, on a "Robinson Crusoe" economy, 2005 (Box 178)
      - Manuel Gottlieb on Schumpeter's theory of capitalism, 1953 (Box 178)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 179)
      - Externalities, exchange, papers by others (Box 179)
      - Second Welfare Theorem, paper by unknown author, and Hurwicz notes (Box 179)
      - Mechanisms and institutions, drafts, 1987-1988, 3 folders (Box 179)
      - Modeling institutions, drafts for AEA meetings, 1988-1990, 4 folders (Box 179)
      - Conference, Econometric Society, Seoul, 1991 (Box 179)
      - Reiter/Hughes, Regulations game, 1991 (Box 179)
    - Drafts and printed material (Box 180)
      - Walker, 1987 (Box 180)
      - Collaboration with Weinberger, decentralizability and intertemporal allocation (Box 180)
      - Collaboration with Weinberger, On smooth balanced Nash mechanisms which implement pareto-optimal performance correspondence in pure exchange economies (Box 180)
      - Collaborations with Walker, Generic non-optimality dominant strategy allocation mechanisms, 1983, 1988, 2 folders (Box 180)
      - Hurwicz, Economic issues in the utilization of knowledge, drafts, 1983 (Box 180)
      - Hurwicz, Perspectives in economics article (photocopy), 1976 (Box 180)
      - Hurwicz, On the interaction between information and incentives in organizations, numerous drafts, 1976, 2 folders (Box 180)
      - Hurwicz, Non-wasteful resource allocation systems, 1976 (Box 180)
      - Collaboration with Richter, Ville Axioms, 1979 (Box 180)
      - Collaboration with Schmeidler, pareto optimality of Nash equilibrium, 1976 (Box 180)
      - Collaboration with Uzawa (Box 180)
    - Drafts, notes, transparencies and printed material (Box 181)
      - Collaboration with Radner and Reiter, decentralized resource allocation, 1973 (Box 181)
      - Hurwicz, stochastic models paper, drafts, 1952 (Box 181)
      - Hurwicz, On the existence of allocation systems whose manipulative Nash equilibria are pareto-optimal..., multiple drafts, 1973-1975, 3 folders (Box 181)
      - Handout, Farmer-Laborer (False Revelation), for Ely Lecture, 1972-1973 (Box 181)
      - Miscellaneous research notes on incentives, tax function, undated (Box 181)
      - Utopia references and quotes, 1976 (Box 181)
      - Hurwicz, "For Dorfman," Non-wasteful resource allocation systems, large draft and notes, 1976 (Box 181)
      - Progress report on research activity for 1974-1975, Univ. of Minnesota (Box 181)
      - On the interaction between information and incentives in organizations, "good copy," 1976 (Box 181)
      - Transparencies (Box 181)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 182)
      - Mechanism design with and without games (Box 182)
      - Walrasian quadratic (Box 182)
      - Collaboration with Saari and Reiter (Box 182)
      - Transversals (Box 182)
      - Lemma B, 1986 (Box 182)
      - Seminar, Indiana (Box 182)
      - Rader (Box 182)
    - Drafts, printed material and professional papers (Box 183)
      - Saari and Simon, Econometrica, 1978 (Box 183)
      - Samuelson, Paul (Box 183)
      - Report of external review committee for Economics Department, Colorado, 1990 (Box 183)
      - Symposium, University of Minnesota, 1994 (Box 183)
    - Clippings, drafts and printed material (Box 184)
      - Choices, games and their topology (Box 184)
      - NBER-NSF conference on decentralization, U. of Pennsylvania, 1985 (Box 184)
      - Clippings, Eastern Europe (Box 184)
      - Joaquin, Thesis, 1984 (Box 184)
    - Clippings, drafts and printed material (Box 185)
      - Koopmans, T. (Box 185)
      - National Science Foundation (Box 185)
      - Clippings, Poland (Box 185)
      - Schmeidler, 1982 (Box 185)
      - Senesh, 1991 (Box 185)
    - Conferences, drafts, notes and printed material (Box 186)
      - Sir William Meyer Endowment Lectures, Madras, 1981 (Box 186)
      - Walrasian and Lindahl allocations at Nash equilibrium points (Box 186)
      - Implementation (Box 186)
      - Barcelona (Box 186)
      - Thompson conference, 1994 July (Box 186)
      - Berkley symposium, 1955 (Box 186)
      - Berlin symposium on planning, 1973 (Box 186)
    - Clippings, drafts, notes and printed material (Box 187)
      - Weather modification, 1965 (Box 187)
      - Reiter (Box 187)
      - Clippings on taxes, retirement, aging (Box 187)
      - Harold Hotelling and the Neoclassical Dream (Box 187)
      - Cores, 1991 (Box 187)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 188)
      - Tokyo conference, 1993 (Box 188)
      - IEA conference, intervention, 1996 June 19 (Box 188)
      - Hildenbrand (Box 188)
      - Externalities, 1997 (Box 188)
      - Harold Hotelling (Box 188)
      - Cores (Box 188)
      - Alphabetical files, Bailey-Bruno (Box 188)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 189)
      - Alphabetical files, Chipman-Pelikan (Box 189)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 190)
      - Alphabetical, Ruys-Srinivasan (4 folders dedicated to Srinivasan) (Box 190)
      - Postlewaite, Endowments, 1979 (Box 190)
    - Clippings, correspondence, drafts, notes and printed material (Box 191)
      - China (Box 191)
      - Comments on Postlewaite, 1979 (Box 191)
      - Calsamiglia (Box 191)
      - Walrasian and Lindahl allocations at Nash Equilibrium points, 1999 (Box 191)
      - Manresa, comments on Hurwicz externalities paper, 3 folders (Box 191)
    - Correspondence, expenses, printed material, transparencies (Box 192)
      - Organizational structures for joint decision making (Box 192)
      - Resource allocation mechanisms (Box 192)
      - Decentralization (Box 192)
    - Clippings, drafts, interview, notes and printed material (Box 193)
      - Specifications, Econometrica, 1951 (Box 193)
      - Notes, history of stability, 1959 (Box 193)
      - Clippings, Democratic Farmer Labor Party (Box 193)
      - Cores (Box 193)
      - Non-wasteful resource allocation systems (Box 193)
      - Excerpts from interview with Hurwicz and Reiter, 1984 May 30 (Box 193)
      - Clippings, economy and weather (Box 193)
      - Collaboration with Sertel, Tunis, 1995 (Box 193)
      - Arrow, Postlewaite, Radner, Reiter, Hurwicz, Report of the Working Group on Markets and Organizations, 1985 (Box 193)
    - Drafts, notecards, notes, printed material and transparencies (Box 194)
      - Core, transparencies (Box 194)
      - Collaboration with Arrow on decentralization (Box 194)
      - Warsaw University, transparencies, 1995 (Box 194)
      - Hurwicz Axioms, notecards on models for decision making (Box 194)
    - Conferences, drafts, notes and printed material (Box 195)
      - Stockholm Conference, 1997, 5 folders (Box 195)
      - On the Dimensional Requirements of Informationally Decentralized Pareto-Satisfactory Processes, 1975 (Box 195)
      - Attempt at Adaption for Individual Feasibility, 1977 (Box 195)
      - Notes, Berkeley symposium, Kuhn-Tucker, 1951 (Box 195)
      - Decentralization (Box 195)
      - Incentive-Compatible Allocation Systems, 1973 (Box 195)
      - Endowment, 1991 (Box 195)
    - Correspondence, drafts, notes, and printed material (Box 196)
      - Who Will Guard the Guardians?, 1998 (Box 196)
      - Informational efficiency narrative, 1997 Aug. 12 (Box 196)
      - Optimality and informational efficiency, 1960 (Box 196)
      - Moscow seminar, 1976 (Box 196)
      - Section V, 1978 (Box 196)
      - Collaboration with Maskin and Postlewaite (Box 196)
      - HMP (Hurwicz-Maskin and Postlewaite) files, 18 Dec. 89, electronic files (2010-0052) (Box 196)
        .LIB and .AP files, contents currently unknown.
      - Papandreou, Andreas, Theory of the Firm, drafts and papers, 1959 and undated (Box 196)
      - Rose, Arnold M., several papers: academic freedom, industrial revolution, irrational choices, 1950s, 1963 (Box 196)
      - Samuelson, Paul, drafts, reprints, including draft of Stolper and Samuelson, Protection and Real Wages, 1939-circa 1950s and undated (Box 196)
      - Mixed professional papers: teaching material; paper by Harsanyi on bargaining model for collaborative game, 1960; collaboration of Hurwicz with Hildreth, 1989; On Increasing Returns (Hurwicz), 2004 (Box 196)
      - unspecified (Box 196)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (Box 197)
      - Collaboration with Reiter (Box 197)
      - Lagrange multipliers (Box 197)
      - Inventing New Institutions, 1987 (Box 197)
      - Marschak, notes to Hurwicz, 1980s (Box 197)
      - Ledyard, note to Hurwicz on equilibrium, with explanation of non-equilibrium, 1975 (Box 197)
      - Pivotal mechanisms (Box 197)
      - Phillips, A.W., Estimation of Systems with Autocorrelated Disturbances, with Hurwicz notes, 1960s (Box 197)
      - Pratt, John (in same folder as Phillips), Utility and Aversion to Risk, unpublished paper at time, 1962 (Box 197)
    - Drafts, notes and printed material (P-R's?) (Box 198)
      - Patinkin, Don, reprints/papers including Market Adjusting and Inventory Equations,, Manufacturing in the U.S., 1946-1961, with notes by Hurwicz (Box 198)
        Along with long 5-page note from Hurwicz to Patinkin.
      - Richter (Box 198)
      - Radner (Box 198)
      - Monopolistic competition (Box 198)
      - Collaboration with Uzawa (Box 198)
      - Unidentified partial drafts, with paper by Quirk, 1970s? (Box 198)
- Teaching Material Series, 1945-2000s, bulk 1980-2000, 7 boxes
  Chiefly consists of photocopies, course notes, transparencies and exam subjects. While as a whole the materials cover Hurwicz's entire career, the majority document his teaching activities after 1980. Documents are arranged in rough chronological order, with the exception of two boxes: one is organized instead by topic, and contains courses on econometrics; the other contains PhD dissertations supervised by Hurwicz.
  - 1945-1981 (Box 199)
  - 1981-1996 (Box 200)
  - 1990s-2000s (Box 201-202)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980s-1990s (Box 203)
  - Econometrics (Box 204)
  - PhD dissertations supervised by Hurwicz (Box 205)
- Oversize Material, 2 folders
  - Newspaper and political manifesto (Box Oversize 16)